Typography, Graphic Design and Global Visual Culture
Helvetica is a documentary film directed by Gary Hustwit.
Helvetica is a feature-length independent film about
typography, graphic design and global visual culture.
It looks at the proliferation of one typeface (which will celebrate its 50th birthday in
2007) as part of a larger conversation about the way type affects our lives.
The film is an exploration of urban spaces in major cities and the type that inhabits them, and a fluid discussion with
renowned designers about their work, the creative process, and the choices and aesthetics behind their use of type.
Himself, played by Michael Bierut.
Himself, played by Neville Brody.
Himself, played by David Carson.
Himself, played by Manfred Schulz.
Himself, played by Massimo Vignelli.
Himself, played by Rick Poynor.
Helvetica is a 2007 American independent feature-length documentary film about
typography and graphic design, centered on the Helvetica typeface.
Directed by Gary Hustwit, it was released in 2007 to coincide with the 50th anniversary of the typeface's
introduction in 1957 and is considered the first of the Design Trilogy by the director.
The film explores themes of designer, advertising,
font, graphic design, typography.